to this module on sql injection
attacks the topic of sql
injections is critically important
for you as you join a company
or you have your own startup
in terms of malicious access to
your data how common are sql
injection attacks well based on
a distribution of web application
vulnerabilities in 2022.
You can see at the very top is
SQL injections at 33 percent.
So I'll mention this a few times
because the driving point that
I'd like to make is that is
generally speaking the concatenation
when you take for instance the
first name and last name as we've
done all semester and concatenated
that that is typically the
problem with an SQL injection
attack. Now throughout the
semester we've worked on the
backend, so we're working directly in
SQL Server. In that case, we're
fine to concatenate. However,
when you have a web development
program or something like Python and
you're getting information from a
user, you'll want to make sure that you
don't concatenate that input from
the user because that can open you
up to an injection attack. And there's
three types of injection attacks
that we'll cover today. These injections
are delivered via what's called
a payload and so it's analogous to
the trojan horse so you think about
the idea of the trojan horse they
built this wooden horse and they you
know put the warriors in it and they
got inside the castle and then of
course it was a fake horse with
lots of warriors and destruction and
so the idea of a payload is similar
to that where you enter into a system
with malicious intent or malicious
code. So an SQL payload is like a
Trojan horse where you're using
either brute force or comment and a
couple of other options to enter into
a database to potentially extract data
or to cause catastrophic damage.
You can delete, drop an entire data
set. So again, the reminder is
never to concatenate user input when
you're not simply typing in the backend
in the SQL Server Management Studio.
An SQL injection inserts some type
of SQL command into the data and
companies to avoid this, obviously
no concatenation, but sometimes
they'll prevent things like
dynamic SQL or stored procedures,
things that potentially introduce
problems and potential access
for vulnerabilities. As you
follow along today, if you would,
open up the website demo.testfire
.net, and this is a sample website
that was developed by Network
Chuck. He's got a great video on SQL
injections on YouTube if you want
to watch his video. but we're
going to use his demo website that
he built. It's a fake bank. When
you access this, make sure that it
shows it's the fake bank and it's
not meant to be real. So the
website that Chuck provides for us
is called Altoro Mutual. And again,
if you log into that, make sure
that you have the right website
typed in based on the prior slide.
Also, as we go through writing
the code to create SQL injections,
you'll want to pause your
screen as you type in the
code that's needed either through
the Altoro website. Once we're
done with that we'll also
introduce an SQL injection into
our own data set. We'll use
the antique data set for today.
So the first type of payload or
malicious string of attack is called
a brute force and a brute force is
simply trial and error in order to
crack the passwords so for instance
I can move over to the Altero website
and I'm going to try to log in
and maybe I'm going to use an a
number and a password and this is a
brute-force attempt I might type in
admin because some websites and the
password the username would be admin
and try some passwords there and
that doesn't work but this is an
example of a brute force login
typically that's done when you have some
information on what the username
and passwords might be now again as
a reminder the idea of the injection
attack is for you to be aware of
it and how it's accomplished but
clearly it's illegal it's something
that you would not want to try on
any website that you don't have
permissions the second type of payload
is called an OR payload and it's
just what you probably think so in
SQL server we have access to some
conjunctions AND or OR and this is
hopefully a good reminder that in SQL
server AND will run before OR and
that's what creates the problem so
for instance in the sample code
that I have I have select star from
customer where last name is equal
to hunt or customer ID is equal to 3
and last name is equal to and then
I use a wildcard character age
percentage so how this runs as a
reminder is it will run the and first so
it'll first say customer ID 3 and
last name is like h and both of these
have to be true and so you'll see
for customer id3 holland does start
with an h and it is customer id3
so this will bring up holland and
then or this can be all of this has
to be true and then it will run this
and it will find anybody with the
last name of hunt and so that's the
way that sql code will run and that
is how the or payload excuse me
is taken advantage of and so if you know
the name of the username
that's where the or
command will come in so I'm going
to switch back to our altoro mutual
and the first thing I'm going to
do is I'm going to test to see if
this is potentially a hackable site
so one thing that What you could
do is you could simply enter an
apostrophe and see what that gives
us. In this case, it gives us a
syntax error, which indicates that
it is possible to breach this particular
account using an SQL injection.
Let me go back to the slides and
show you how that would work.
This is an example of the injection
that we'll do later on, but it
builds the idea of the importance
of these apostrophes in terms of
SQL injections. So in this particular
case I just created a variable
and I set that variable to Heinz.
Now to do a character data remember
we put a single quote around the
character data so for this we
put a single quote around Heinz.
However when I print this when I run
this you'll notice that Heinz
doesn't have the apostrophes and so
if we're going to use this data from
a front end to a back end. Assume
this is like the front end, so
we're on a website. So in order
to have this Heinz work, we need
to put a single quote around Heinz.
And so what happens is, again, if
I try to do this without the single
quote, then of course we get an
error message because it can't figure
out Heinz. We need to put that quote
around there. So this for now just
think of this as the back end so
this is this is the we're declaring a
variable we're setting it we're so
assume the bottom code here is the
back end code and you can see here
where we're adding it we're taking
Heinz which doesn't have the single
quote and we're adding a single quote
to each side so we have a we have the
two quotes wrapped around a single
quote which makes or tells the
system to write a single quote so we
have a single quote here and then
we have the word Heinz and then it
wants to put a single quote after
that so how we trick the system is
instead of using their single quote
we close it with our own single quote
we'll put another one right here
and that will allow us to type in
additional code so let's go back to the
website and try that so again on the
website when I typed in something
like admin and I put a single quote
and got a syntax error rather than
a regular error. What that suggests
is when we put that apostrophe in
there it confused the SQL code because
it has our apostrophe now and then
it has its second apostrophe, the
one that it tried to put in. So it
can't quite figure out what to do
with that extra apostrophe that we
put in there. But by putting that
apostrophe in there that closes off
that part of code and then we can do
some other code to follow that and
make the changes that we want and the
first option we have is the or
payload let's go back and take a look
at the slide on the or payload so
I'll go back up a few and you can see
here what's happening is we're going
to say we're admin assuming that
the admin is correct we're going to
put the quote here which closes off
this instead of having the computer
close it off and then we simply use
the OR payload and we're going to
indicate that one is equal to one.
And why do we leave this last part blank?
Is because remember the system
wants to put in the quote and they
typically want to put it right here
but we put it here allowing us to add
additional code and by leaving it
off here the final thing it will do
is say oh we need to add the single
quote to this and then we will
evaluate this to true or false let's
try our or injection attack we know
that the username is admin we don't
know the password here but we're
going to open up the single quote
allowing us to type anything in here
in this case we want to create that
conjunction where one is equal to
one and then any password so we
have admin a single apostrophe that
closes the name off and then we add
this conjunction or one is equal to
one and in this case it is true and
because it's true it lets us in.
Bam! So that's our use of an or
where we're tricking it to create
a true scenario and because it's
true it allows us into the system
okay let's back up and go to the
next one so the third type of
injection attack is called a comment
payload and if you remember when
you want to comment on code you
would use for instance the double
dash right and everything after
that would turn green and so that
allows you to make a comment well
in this particular case if you think
about writing admin and we put
that single quote up and then
following the single quote we do dash
dash that would get rid of anything
after the initial ask of the username
which would make the username
true all we have is the admin
and then nothing else matters
because it's all been commented out
and so let's try that as our second
type of or third type I guess
of attack so we have admin, the
single quote, and then we, not the
equals, but we use the dash dash.
Any type of password will
work because that will be
commented out and we're in.
So that's the second type of,
third type of attack. So we
have the brute force, we have
the or payload, and then we
have the comment payload.
All right, let's go back and
take a look at what's the fourth
scenario that combines the use of the
OR payload and the comment payload
and this occurs if you don't
know the username for the system.
Let's take a look at that one.
So if if we don't know the username
then we can use this unknown user
payload which combines the apostrophe
and OR payload so we have the OR
payload and then it also uses the
comment payload and so what we're
suggesting here is we don't know
what it is we're going to close we're
going to have the first quote provided
by the system we're going to close
that off so it's just basically
blank but you could put something
there is just we're going to have that
and then we're going to use the OR
payload and following the 1 equals
1 command we'll use the double dash
and by using the double dash what
that allows us to do is to comment
out anything related to the password
so this is a combination of both
of those so go ahead and try that
pause the screen and then for your in
-class activity or video activity you'll
upload some of these as requested
by the in-class or video activity
so I'm going to go back to the
website and I'm going to combine
these I don't know the name of it so
I'm going to put in apostrophe and
then in this case I'll use the or
payload and do one is equal to one
and then I'll double that I'll double
dash that and then for the password
nothing would matter there and in
that case it gets us in based on
using a combined or payload and the
comment payload so all of those give
us access to override effectively a
concatenated key and the main part
of it is we put that apostrophe to
close off the name where it thinks
the names and And then we can add
malicious code. So now let's go
ahead and take a look at our own SQL
server using the antique data set and
set up a similar type of scenario.
And before we do so, this is a
relatively famous cartoon clip.
And in this particular
case, you can see in the
first square on the left,
it says, hi, this is your
son's school. We've run
into some computer trouble.
Oh dear, did he break something in
a way? and then they ask did you
really name your son the name and
then you can see they added that
apostrophe after the apostrophe then
they've gone in with the semicolon
started some new code in this particular
case they dropped table students
and then see the double dash there
to comment everything out and
then the retort is yeah we named
little little bobby tables we call him
so the point here is it's fairly
easy with that apostrophe if the
database has concatenated data for
user input all right to do our own
internal sql injection we need to
change our sql output to text and so
under tools and options you have
a option to go results to text and
so i'm going to do that, and as I'm
switching over to the screen, just
as a reminder, I think mine's already
set up there, but if I go Tools,
Options, and then Query Results,
we have results to text, so you
would select that and say OK. You
can change that back later, and then
once you've selected it, you'll
have to indicate a new query before
that new setting will take place.
So now I'm in the antiques data set.
So if you can load that, go ahead and
pause the screen if you need that.
So select star from the customer
data set. And I run that. And now
we have this text outcome instead of
the grid outcome that we typically
use. and so we're going to go ahead
and set up the injection attack
and to do that we have a slide and
you can copy this first code here
but the first code here is if you
would declare this variable and set
it to Heinz initially and then
let's print it to make sure that it
works and this is a good reminder
of why that apostrophe takes place
so I'm going to indicate using the
comment that this would be an example
of the front end so for instance
like a website and this is what
we'll be able to modify we won't be
able to modify the backend and so
to do that we're going to declare
a variable and in this case we can
say the name of the variable we want
to declare so we're just going to
call it at s and then we give it a
data type and so this would be as
and on mine I'm just checking I put
in bar chart 200 which is pretty
big and then we can set it and there's
a couple ways to do these variables
we'll do in 4330 but for now we'll
just set at s equal to Heinz.
Now to do this we need to
put in the single quote
print at s just allows us
to see what we've done here
and so you can see that Heinz is
the output but there is no quotes
around here and if we run this
code without the quotes we get the
error message and so we do have to
have the single quotes however on
the on the on the back end when it
reads it it has to add these quotes
around it otherwise it will give
that error message on the back
end and so this would be the front
end now on the next slide we'll
go ahead and type in the back end
and let me flip over to this slide
and this is the back end if you would
pause the screen and go ahead and
type this in and the critical part
on this back end is where we're
going to take Heinz that doesn't have
the quotes around it and we'll add
a single quote to the front and a
single quote to the back and that's
where we can artificially put a
single quote to the back in just a bit
in order to create our malicious code
so go ahead and type that in I'll
switch over and in this case we're
going to declare another variable
set equal to and we'll
create a select statement
here we need to have it
in a single quote as well.
And I'll go ahead and type that out.
All right, so I have it typed in
the back end. And what's happening
is we've given the name Heinz. And
Heinz, and I commented out the print
here because we don't need to see
that show up. But what's happening
now is the back end is taking at s,
which is Heinz here, using dynamic
SQL beyond the scope of 3330. But
just consider this to be the back
end like the bank is, like the
demonstration, it's just we're doing
it both the back and the front end
at one place. But what it's doing
is it's taking Heinz that doesn't
have an apostrophe, it's putting one
in back, excuse me, it's putting
one in front and then one in back.
And if I run it the way that
it's meant to be set up, you
can see here's the code these
items here add that single
quote here to the front and
the back and therefore it runs
so similar to the bank now is
what i can do i can't affect
the back end but i can infect
the front end is i can go ahead
and put that second apostrophe
in and if i run this code
I get this error message similar
to what the bank had so it's
saying we have a problem with that
character string and then we can
go in and type in the injection
attack which will get rid of the
syntax error and to do that we add
that apostrophe that I did we're
going to close this off and
then we're going to say print go
Aggies. We have a double quote
here and a double quote here and in
order to finish up the other quotes
it's kind of a trust me and I'll
show you another way to do that.
We can use a comment but we
have one two three four five in
order to completely close off this
code. So let's go back to our code
and go ahead and type that in.
so we've created this we're going
to close that off with a semicolon
and then the next thing we're going to do
is just kind of an
innocent print go aggies
injection we have the
information typed in
one two and then we need three four five
in order for that to work and now
it says one row this is what's
happened we have this the quote around
the Heinz that's that second quote
and then we indicate print Aggies
and we it we added this apostrophe
here to close off the code and it
runs it just fine but in addition
to running that it also says go
eggy's injection and this is where you
could put in something more malicious
than simply go eggy's injection
you could put in for instance drop
table and in this case we're just
going to use the dash dash which
is similar to the comment we need
to close it with an apostrophe and
so go ahead and type this in for your
final SQL injection attack and we
get an interesting message here.
So if I say drop table and we're
working on the employee table
and then we'll use the comment comment we
end with the parenthesis
around everything
and it didn't drop but there's
a reason it didn't drop because
it's a parent table right and
because we have referential integrity
we would have to drop the child
table before we drop the parent
table so that gives us one
level of insulation between this
injection attack working but if I
said drop table and I knew the name
of a table, I could drop the
child table, and that's far more
malicious, obviously, than just
saying print SQL injection attack.
So I hope this provided an interesting
and kind of scary version or
angle of SQL with SQL injections.
Again, the big takeaway is when
you're working with the front end
and receiving information, never
concatenate that user input and each
business will have probably their
own procedures for doing that we
did dynamic sql on the back end
and that made it vulnerable using
those variables that we declared so
that made it a concatenation using
dynamic sql and so finally as a
reminder sql injections without
permissions is highly illegal and
probably don't want to think about
it so i hope this was an enjoyable
look and lesson. Have a great day
and we will see you next lesson.